Before explaining which agent is
what, I will show you how an agent
works in real time.
Let's say you are a fresher.
You have a resume and you want to
apply for a specific job.
There is a job description for that
job.
My problem is that you don't know
how to cater or how to change your
resume based on job description.
We don't know what is an ATS score,
how to write a cover letter,
how to message to HR.
You don't know any of these things.
So for that, I have built this agent
system.
So let's say I have this resume.
Let's say this is my resume.
Let's say this is a sample resume.
I will copy the contents of this
resume.
And then I will put in the first
section which has your resume.
And I go to the LinkedIn.
And in LinkedIn, I searched for AI
engineer jobs at the entry level in
the Hyderabad location.
And I will
copy the content of this job
description.
Okay.
And then we will put it in the job
description card.
And the job role is applied AI
engineer.
So I will put it here.
Applied AI engineer.
Okay. Now do you know what you have
to do?
Just click on run agent pipeline.
Do you know what this does?
It analyzes your resume.
It will analyze your strengths and
weaknesses.
Everything will give you detailed
steps.
Your top keywords, seniority level,
tools and technologies.
Must have skills. Nice to have
skills.
After that, based on the job
description, based on the resume,
it will try to match.
How well are we suited for that job?
And it will give you a score.
See here.
Score is 28 by 100.
Which is very very bad.
And it will give you the summary of
that score.
Why it is giving 28.
After that, what are your math
skills?
What are your weak points?
And what are you missing from the
job description?
It gives you everything step by
step.
And sections to improve as well.
And then after this, it will rewrite
your bullet points.
That is, based on the job
description, how to change the
content in your resume.
It will give you suggestions.
This is your original content.
And rewrite in something like this.
And why?
It will give you every single thing.
And this is not the only thing.
After this, you have to send an
email to the HR.
You have to send a message.
So what do you have to write in that
message?
Even that will be provided by this
agent.
If you look at this one.
Cover letter.
Dear hiring manager.
It has all the details about what
you can message to HR.
And other than all this,
there is one more agent.
Which is called a critic review.
It validates all the content that we
have given.
It validates and gives a score.
That score is less than 8.
And the entire process will restart
from the first to the last.
But if you look at it here.
The score we got is 7 by 10.
And it is revising the everything
guys.
It is doing a second attempt.
And it will do it until it gets 8 by
10.
So let's wait until that.
And right now it is doing revision
guys.
After that, it will change every
single thing.
And it will also provide.
And if you want to prepare for that
job.
What kind of interview questions
that you can expect.
So now it has done the revision.
After the revision.
Now we got the score as 8 by 10.
Now all the suggestions are here.
And now it is generating the
interview questions.
That you can expect for that job
role.
Isn't it interesting?
All this you cannot achieve with
just a single prompt in charge GPT
guys.
This is a proper agent.
Running locally in my machine.
And there are multiple agents
running in the back end of this
website.
To achieve this task.
These are called AI agents.
And this is going to be the future.
Now in this video.
I will not tell you how to build all
this.
The purpose of this video is.
I want to teach you or tell you the
difference between.
What is LLM?
What are automations?
What are workflows?
What are agents?
So let's start everything from
scratch.
Before we go into that.
For those who don't know.
My name is Balaji Chippada.
And I have 80 years of experience in
the field of AI and ML.
And I want to teach all of these
concepts to you in Telugu.
So let's start with the first topic.
LLM.
What is LLM?
Large Language Model.
You already know.
If you have used charge GPT.
Gemini.
Cloud.
All of these are the applications.
They built using LLMs.
So these applications are there in
the back end.
These LLMs are there.
So how do LLMs work?
It is very simple.
If you give a question.
That question goes to LLM.
And that will give you the answer.
Let's say.
Maybe you asked.
Rewrite my resume.
And it will rewrite every single
point in your resume.
Maybe.
You have to write an email to your
manager.
Go to charge GPT.
You will say.
Write an email to my manager.
Regarding a sick leave.
And it will give you the output.
These are called LLMs.
And these LLMs have a lot of
limitations.
Those limitations are.
It doesn't know your personal
details.
It doesn't know your email.
It doesn't know your address.
And it cannot connect to your
calendar.
Whatever meetings you have.
What to do.
So it doesn't have any of the
external knowledge.
Unless you specifically provide in
the chart.
And the second limitation is.
It will give you the answer only if
you give a question.
They cannot do anything.
This is the major limitation for
large language models.
So to simply explain LLMs.
You brought a really intelligent
person to a room.
He will give you the answer only if
you go and talk to him.
Otherwise he will not do anything.
So those are called LLMs.
Hopefully it is clear.
And now the second part.
Which are AI workflows.
What are AI workflows?
Now a person or a human will define
the steps that AI needs to take.
To simply explain.
Imagine you have to daily post an AI
news on Instagram.
What do you normally do?
You will open the websites.
You will search for important AI
news.
And you will read each and every
article.
After that you will take the
summary.
You will create the captions.
And according to those captions.
You will create an image or a
corosal.
After that you finally open the
Instagram and upload it.
That is the whole process.
Now this whole process is called
workflow.
Now an LLM can do all this workflow.
So what do you define?
Every morning at 8 am this workflow
has to start.
After that.
An LLM.
It could be ChargePT or GROG or
Gemini.
It will go and search for the top AI
articles.
And then it will collect it.
After collecting it.
It will summarize everything.
After that.
What does another LLM do?
From that summary.
It will try to create an Instagram
corosal.
And also the captions.
And then what does another LLM do?
It will post on top of Instagram.
So this entire process.
That is defined by the humans.
Is called a workflow.
That an LLM can follow.
So to do all these automations.
We have different websites.
May be Ni10.
Make.com.
Zapier.
But we will talk about those in the
later sections.
But the problem here is.
When unexpected situations come.
The LLM will struggle guys.
May be let's say.
Today's AI news is very boring.
So that boring content method.
It will make a corosal.
It will not think.
And it will say.
This is a boring.
I need to think about something
else.
So what does it do?
Because it will only follow.
The predefined steps.
That you have defined already.
It will not think from its own
memory.
So to put it simply.
Workflow is a predefined step.
By the humans.
And it will not use.
Its own knowledge or intelligence.
To make it better.
So that is where.
The agent comes into the picture.
How to make these things better.
Now the third one.
Which is the very interesting one.
Which are called agents.
What is agents?
To put it simply.
You will not define the steps.
You will define the goal.
What is our first example?
We have a resume.
And then job description.
And I want the agent.
To make my resume.
As good as possible.
To apply for this job.
What does the agent do for that?
First it analyzes.
What is the content in our resume?
What is the content in the job
description?
These two are done by math.
What are the skills that I am
lacking?
What are the things that I need to
work on?
All these are given.
In the feedback loop.
Another agent comes.
Using that knowledge.
And reasoning.
If it is not correct.
It will generate again.
Until you get a perfect score.
It is going to return and rerun.
This is called react pattern.
This is where agent is incorporating
its intelligence.
So by doing all this.
Finally your resume.
How to change your resume.
What you need to learn.
How you need to prepare.
A full fledged process.
To think about yourself.
Is called agent.
This is what is called an agentic
behaviour.
The only difference is.
It will not stop.
After giving an answer.
It will think.
It will rethink.
And it will reason.
And then it will work towards a
goal.
This is what an agent will do.
So simple formula.
A agent is equal to LLM plus goal
plus reasoning plus tools plus
feedback loop.
So in our resume example.
Until we get a score of 8 out of 10.
It will do the reasoning.
That is called feedback loop as
well.
So now the main question.
Why do you need to learn all this.
Because in future.
Many companies.
Will not hire those who use charge
GPT.
Almost everyone uses charge GPT.
Where is the real value.
Can you identify the problem.
Can you break it into chunks.
Can you design any workflow.
Can you create tools.
Can you create MCP servers.
Can you add guard rails.
Can you make the output reliable.
If you know all these answers.
Companies will run behind you guys.
Come and work with us.
This is the new skill.
This is where the gap is.
This is where I want to focus on.
So how will our work be in the
future.
Not to automate normal tasks.
By using AI.
How you can build agents that can
think.
And automate and build your tasks
for you.
That is the real future.
So to summarize everything.
What is LLM.
Large language models.
You provide an input and it provides
an output.
That's it.
It cannot do anything.
And second part which are AI
workflows.
What is AI workflows.
A person.
Will define the steps.
And the LLM.
Will do all of these steps.
But in this process.
It will not use its brain.
It will just do what the human says.
That is what a workflow is.
And third part is AI agents.
What do agents do.
They work towards a goal.
You give a task.
To achieve that task.
It will do anything.
It will reason. It will think.
It will rethink.
It will re -reason.
And it will search the website.
Any single thing.
Until that goal is achieved.
How a person uses a brain.
LLM will use its brain.
And the tools.
Like MCP's.
To achieve the task.
That is what we call it as an agent.
The next question is.
How do these agents build.
So that is where.
I have made a dedicated road map
video.
In 2026.
If you want to become an AI agent.
What are the things you need to
learn.
What should you learn.
What should you do.
To become an AI engineer.
So that video is linked in the
description below.
And I want everyone to check this
out.
And one more thing guys.
If this video gets good likes and
comments.
I will show you.
How to build that.
The tool that we initially
displayed.
Which will match your resume and job
description.
And maybe I will do a live video on
top of that.
So it is up to you.
And guys.
If you like this content.
Subscribe to the channel.
And click that bell icon to get
notified daily.